Guide to the Thomas D. Kimball Papers, 1851-1867
Thomas D. Kimball papers 1851-1867
Kimball, Thomas D.
1.5 Linear Feet 650Items
Duke University. David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The papers of Thomas D. Kimball, Civil War Army officer of Oxford, Worcester County, Massachusetts, were purchased by the Rubenstein Library in September 1981.
Collection Overview
The papers of Thomas D. Kimball span the period 1851 to 1867 with the majority of the papers dating from 1862 to 1865. They consist primarily of official communications and documents relating to Company A, 2d Massachusetts Heavy Artillery and Company G., 51st Massachusetts Volunteer Militia Infantry, during the period they were occupying New Bern, N.C., after its capture by Union troops. Kimball was Captain first in the 51st Regiment and later in the 2nd Massachusetts Heavy Artillery Regiment. The collection is divided into five series: correspondence; financial papers; orders; regimental reports; and miscellany.
Regimental reports comprise the bulk of the collection and are divided into two subseries, personnel and other monthly and quarterly reports, concerning the companies' supplies. Personnel records include returns (reports indicating changes in company personnel), records of target practice, volunteer enlistment papers, descriptive lists, and discharge papers.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
United States.--Army.--Massachusetts Heavy Artillery Regiment, 2d (1863-1865).--Company A.
United States.--Army.--Massachusetts Infantry Regiment, 51st (1862-1863).--Company G.
New Bern (N.C.) -- History -- Civil War, 1861-1865
North Carolina -- Craven County -- New Bern
Contents of Collection
- Correspondence, 1851-1867, (3 folders)
  - Correspondence (Box 1)
- Financial Papers, 1863-1864 and undated
  - Financial papers (Box 1)
- Orders:
  - Various, 1863-1864 Aug. (Box 1)
  - (Volume), 1863 July-Dec.
  - (Volume), 1864 Jan.-Aug.
  - Printed Orders and Circulars 1864 Feb.-1865 June and undated
  - (Volume), 1865 Jan.-Aug.
- Regimental Reports:
  - Personnel: (Box 2)
    - Returns, 1862 Dec.-1865 Aug.
    - Records of Target Practice, 1864 June-Sept.
    - Pay Vouchers, 1865
    - Volunteer Enlistments and Final Statements
    - Descriptive lists, (2 folders)
    - Discharge Papers
    - Miscellany, 1863 Apr.-1865 Aug. and undated
  - Company:
    - Monthly Returns of Clothing, 1863 Sept.-1865 July, (4 folders) (Box 3)
    - Quarterly Returns of Clothing, 1862 Sept.-1864 May
    - Quarterly Returns of Ordnance and Ordnance Stores, 1862-1865 and undated, (4 folders) (Box 4)
    - Monthly Returns of Quartermaster's Stores, 1864 May-1865 July
- Miscellany
  - Miscellaneous files (Box 4)
- Oversize Volume:
  - Company Morning Reports, 1862 Nov.-1863 June (Folder 1)